

10 Akron Street, Cambridge, Massachusetts

□+16178030901 | ▼ytoriumi@gsd.harvard.edu,yoji.toriumi@gmail.com | 🗖 yoji-toriumi

## **Summary** \_

Urban planner with engineering bachelor's and master's degrees and nine years of experience in international development cooperation. Proven ability to work in teams as well as individually as is evidenced by the fact that led a section in JICA Nepal Office and JICA HQ. Highly interested in contributing to sound urban growth with skills and knowledge of urban planning, data analysis, and statistics gained throughout my career thus far. Left JICA in July 2021 for pursuing a Master of Urban Planning degree at Harvard University Graduate School of Design and studying urban analytics.

## **Education**

## **Graduate School of Design, Harvard University**

MASTER OF URBAN PLANNING

Graduate School of Engineering, The University of Tokyo

MASTER OF URBAN ENGINEERING (GPA: 3.88/4.0)

**Faculty of Engineering, The University of Tokyo** 

BACHELOR OF URBAN ENGINEERING

#### Cambridge, United States

2021 - present

Tokyo, Japan

2010 - 2012

Tokyo, Japan

2006 - 2010

## Portfolios and Relevant Coursework at the GSD

- Spatial Analysis (High Pass)
- Quantitative Analysis (High Pass)
- Qualitative Analysis (High Pass)
- Representation for Planners

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

# Financial Cooperation Implementation Department, Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA)

July, 2020 - July, 2021

ASSISTANT DIRECTOR

· Managed a section composed of 11 technical experts

- · Managed appraising design and cost analysis of more than 30 financial projects
- Managed contracts for projects interrupted by Covid-19
- Enhanced effectiveness of financial projects by advising on technical and managerial aspects

### JICA Nepal Office, Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA)

Kathmandu, Nepal

Tokyo, Japan

July, 2016 - June, 2020

REPRESENTATIVE

- Formulated and managed more than ten urban environment and disaster risk reduction (DRR) projects in Nepal
- Developed country cooperation strategy for Nepal
- · Coordinated with stakeholders, including government officials, consultants, and development partners
- Improved urban development management and DRR capacity of the Nepalese government

# Infrastructure & Peacebuilding Department, Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA)

Tokyo, Japan

DEPUTY ASSISTANT DIRECTOR

May, 2014 - June, 2016

April, 2012 - April, 2014

- Formulated and managed technical assistance and grant projects in developing countries' urban development sectors
- Led housing reconstruction project in Nepal (Won JICA' Presidential Award, which is given to exemplary projects)

### South Asia Department, Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA)

Tokyo, Japan

STAFF MEMBER

- Formulated urban development loan projects in Pakistan
- Developed country cooperation strategy for Pakistan
- Strengthened relationship between Japan and Pakistan

JANUARY 2022 YOJI TORIUMI · CURRICULUM VITAE



1st-Class Architect Japan

2019

**Japan Statistical Society Certificate Grade 2** 

Japan 2014

## **Publications**

- 1. Nagami, K., Miyano, T., Nishimura, N., Toriumi, Y., Tsukahara, N., & Nakamura, A. (2020). Practical approaches to build back better with inclusive recovery from earthquake disasters: A discussion based on the 2015 nepal earthquake recovery project by JICA. *JICA Ogata Sadako Research Institute for Peace and Development*.
- 2. Kidokoro, T., Shima, N., Kashiwazaki, K., & (eds.). (2015). *Urban communities in asia and africa: Structuring logic of "Handmade Cities" and the practice of empowerment*. Gakugei Shuppansha.
- 3. Kidokoro, T., & Toriumi, Y. (2013). Formation of social ecosystem space of informal settlements in the case of dharavi in mumbai, india. *Journal of Architecture and Planning*, 78(687).

## Skills

## **Coding**

- R (Tidyverse, tidycensus, tidytransit, sf, leaflet, shiny)
- Phthon (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, scikit-learn)

## **Mapping**

· ArcGIS, QGIS

### Adobe

• Indesign, Illustrator, Photoshop

## Microsoft

• Word, Excel, Power Point

## Awards\_

### **Fulbright Scholarship**

FULBRIGHT PROGRAM JAPAN 2021

#### JICA's Presidential Award

Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA)

# Languages \_\_\_\_\_

## **Japanese**

NATIVE

#### **English**

EXCELLENT